So the neural network architecture that we use for diffusion models is a UNet.
我们用于扩散模型的
神经网络架构是一个UNet。
And the most important thing that you need to know about a UNet is that
关于UNet最重要的是，
it is taking as input this image and it's producing as output something of the same size as that image, but here it is that predicted noise.
它将图像作为输入，
输出与图像大小相同的预测噪声。
UNets have been around for a very long time, since 2015, and it was first used for image segmentation.
UNet已经存在
很长时间了，自2015年以来，
它首次被用于图像分割。
so it's used a lot in self-driving car research.
因此在自动驾驶汽车
研究中得到了广泛应用。
But what's special about UNets is just that its input and outputs are the same size.
但UNet的特殊之处在于
其输入和输出大小相同。
And what it does is it first embeds information about this input,
它首先将这个输入的信息嵌入，
so it downsamples with a lot of convolutional layers into an embedding that compresses all that information into a small amount of space,
通过许多卷积层将其降采样
到一个压缩了所有信息的嵌入中，
and then it upsamples with the same number of upsampling blocks into the output back out for its task.
然后用相同数量的
上采样块将输出返回到任务中。
And in this case, that task is to predict the noise that was applied to this image.
在这个例子中，它的任务
就是预测应用到这个图片上的噪音。
And if you want to look a little bit deeper, which we'll do together,
如果你想深入了解，
我们可以一起来看看，
is that each of these named blocks here are also shown in the code with the same names.
这些命名块在代码中
也用相同的名称显示。
And this predicted noise is the same dimension, 16,16 by 3, of the original input image.
这个预测的噪声与原始输入
图像的尺寸相同，16x16x3。
What's also great about this UNet is that it can take in additional information.
UNet的另一个优点是
它可以接收额外的信息。
So it's compressed that image to understand what's going on, but it can also take in more information.
所以它压缩了图像以了解发生
了什么，但也可以接收更多信息。
And so what information do we want to include?
那么我们想要包括拿些信息呢？
Well, one thing that's really important for these models is the time embedding.
对于这些模型来说，
一个非常重要的信息就是时间嵌入。
And so this is an embedding that kind of tells the model what the time step is,
这是一种告诉模型时间步长的嵌入，
and therefore what kind of noise level we need.
因此我们需要某种级别的噪音。
And all you have to do for this time embedding is you embed it into some kind of vector,
对于这个时间嵌入，你需要
做的就是将它嵌入到一个向量中，
and you can add it into these upsampling blocks.
然后将其添加到这些上采样块中。
Another piece of information that could be useful is a context embedding.
另一个有用的信息是上下文嵌入。
We'll do more of this later, but all that context embedding does is it helps you control what the model generates.
我们稍后会更深入地讨论
这个，但上下文嵌入的作用就是
帮助你控制模型生成的内容。
We'll discuss this a bit more later.
稍后我们会再讨论这个问题。
And for that context embedding, you can just multiply it in.
对于这个上下文嵌入，
你只需要将它乘进去就可以了。
Great.
很好！
So what does that look like in code?
那么这在代码中是什么样子的呢？
Here you can see a context embedding.
这里你可以看到一个上下文嵌入。
This is just one of them.
这只是其中之一。
And then here you see the time embedding.
然后在这里你可以看到时间嵌入。
And in the upsampling block, all you have to do again, just like in this diagram,
在上采样模块中，你需要
做的就是像图示中那样，
you multiply the context embedding with the upsampling block, and you add the time embedding.
把上下文嵌入乘以上采样块，
然后加上时间嵌入。
Cool.
很好！
So now in the notebook, in the forward pass of the model, so this is running the model,
那么现在，在 Notebook 的
模型前向传递中，这就是运行模型，
you can see some of these down, down, down blocks, and then also these up, up, up blocks here.
你可以看到一些这样的下采样块，
然后也有这些上采样块。
And again, here are your context and time embeddings.
再次强调，这里是
你的上下文和时间嵌入。
We have two of them here for each of those up blocks.
我们在这里为每一个
上采样块都设置了两个。
And how these down and up blocks are defined is up here in initialization for the UNet.
这些上采样和下采样块是如何定义
的，是在UNet的初始化部分定义的。
And so for the down, this is what a UNet down looks like.
所以对于下采样，这就是
一个UNet下采样的样子。
But they are just convolutional blocks.
但它们就是卷积块。
And in the next video, you'll learn how to train this neural network.
在下一个视频中，你将
学会如何训练这个神经网络。